<pmid version="1">28777224</pmid>
<title>Short-term Results of Trabeculectomy Using Adjunctive Intracameral Bevacizumab Versus Mitomycin C: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</title>
<abstract>
<abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the outcome of trabeculectomy using adjunctive intracameral <a1>bevacizumab</a1> versus intraoperative <a2>mitomycin</a2> C (MMC).</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">In this double-blind, randomized clinical trial 87 eyes of 87 <p>patients</p> with primary open-angle or pseudoexfoliation glaucoma were assigned to each treatment group (44 cases received 1.25 mg intracameral bevacizumab at the end of operation and in 43 cases MMC was applied during surgery). Success was defined as intraocular <oc>pressure</oc> (IOP) between 6 and 21 mm Hg and at least 30% IOP drop with (qualified) or without (complete) glaucoma medications without additional glaucoma surgery.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">The follow-up time was 17.12±2.58 months in the bevacizumab group and 17.23±2.42 months in the MMC group (P=0.845). The preoperative IOP was <r1>29.17±3.94</r1> and <r2>28.8±4.08 mm Hg</r2> in the bevacizumab and MMC groups, respectively (P=0.689). Last visit IOP was 17.41±3.11 mm Hg in the bevacizumab group and 15.34±3.62 mm Hg in the MMC group (P&amp;lt;0.009). Compared with baseline, IOP drop at last visit was 11.76±5.51 and 13.43±5.92 in the bevacizumab and MMC groups, respectively (P=0.207). At last visit, complete success was achieved in 25 cases (61%) of bevacizumab group and 23 cases (66%) of MMC group (P=0.669). Early filtering bleb leak was more prevalent in bevacizumab group (29% vs. 11%).</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">A single 1.25 mg dose of intracameral bevacizumab improves the success of trabeculectomy comparable with MMC; however, it increases the risk of early filtering bleb leakage.</abstracttext>
</abstract>