<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   10682964
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    Oral carbonic anhydrase inhibitors used to treat glaucoma have significant systemic side effects. Brinzolamide 1.0%, a new topical ocular carbonic anhydrase inhibitor, is effective apparently without significant systemic side effects. This study was performed to establish the long term safety and efficacy of brinzolamide 1.0% two and three times daily for primary open angle
    <p>
     glaucoma
    </p>
    and ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    An _POFT_, multicenter, double masked, parallel, controlled study was conducted. Patients were randomized to
    <a1>
     brinzolamide
    </a1>
    two or three times daily or
    <a2>
     timolol
    </a2>
    0.5% twice daily in a _RATIO_ ratio (_POP_, and 75, respectively). Intraocular pressure was measured at _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily at eligibility and _POFT_, _POFT_, _POFT_, 9, 12, 15, and 18. Efficacy was based on intraocular pressure
    <oc>
     reduction
    </oc>
    from baseline. Safety was also evaluated.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    All regimens produced clinically relevant and statistically significant _PVAL_ intraocular pressure reductions from baseline. Mean changes in intraocular pressure trough measurements ranged from
    <r1>
     2.7 to 3.9 mmHg
    </r1>
    with brinzolamide twice daily dosing and 2.8 to 3.8 mmHg three times daily dosing compared with
    <r2>
     4.7 to 5.6 mmHg
    </r2>
    with timolol. The intraocular pressure reductions with brinzolamide two and three times daily were clinically and statistically equivalent. One hundred forty four patients were discontinued from the study after randomization with the most common reasons being the occurrence of an adverse event (46), inadequate intraocular pressure control (23), patient decision unrelated to study medication (11), lost to follow up (16), and noncompliance (9). Adverse events were nonserious and resolved without sequelae. There were no clinically relevant changes in safety parameters. Brinzolamide produced less ocular discomfort (burning/stinging) than timolol, and total carbonic anhydrase inhibition levels remained below that known to cause systemic side effects.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Brinzolamide produced significant and equivalent reductions in intraocular pressure when dosed two and three times daily for _POFT_. Brinzolamide was safe and well tolerated by patients, with minimal ocular discomfort.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   The long-term safety and efficacy of brinzolamide 1.0% (azopt) in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension. The Brinzolamide Long-Term Therapy Study Group.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>