<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   10837379
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="AIMS" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the effects on intraocular pressure  and side effects of monotherapy with either
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    or
    <a2>
     dorzolamide
    </a2>
    in patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    224
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension were recruited to a 3 month open labelled study. Previous glaucoma medications were washed out and the patients were randomised to receive either latanoprost 0.005% once daily or dorzolamide 2% three times daily.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Of 224 patients 213 were included in the analysis of efficacy. After 3 months, latanoprost reduced mean baseline diurnal
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    from 27.2 (Surgery , Mean 3.0) mmHg by
    <r1>
     8.5 (3.3) mmHg
    </r1>
    . The corresponding figures for dorzolamide were 27.2 (3.4) and
    <r2>
     5.6 (2.6) mmHg
    </r2>
    . The difference of 2.9 mmHg (95% Confidence Interval: 2.3-3.6) was highly significant (p&lt;0.001, ANCOVisual Acuity). Latanoprost reduced Intraocular Pressure at peak by 8.6 mmHg (32%) compared with 6.2 mmHg (23%) for dorzolamide, and the difference of 2.4 mmHg was significant (p&lt;0.001, ANCOVisual Acuity). The corresponding figures at trough were 8.1 mmHg (31%) for latanoprost and 4.7 mmHg (17%) for dorzolamide, a significant difference of 3.4 mmHg (p&lt;0.001, ANCOVisual Acuity). Both drugs were well tolerated systemically and locally.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Latanoprost was superior to dorzolamide in reducing the Intraocular Pressure, judged both from the effect on Intraocular Pressure at peak and trough and by the effect on diurnal Intraocular Pressure.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   A comparison of latanoprost and dorzolamide in patients with glaucoma and ocular hypertension: a 3 month, randomised study. Ireland Latanoprost Study Group.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>