<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   11336940
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the intraocular pressure lowering effect and side effects of
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    0.005% once daily with
    <a2>
     unoprostone
    </a2>
    0.12% twice daily.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Sixty
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with primary open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension were randomized to receive either latanoprost once daily in the evening and placebo once daily in the morning, or unoprostone twice daily in the morning and evening. The study was double masked and followed a crossover design with two treatment periods of _POFT_ separated by a _POFT_ washout period. The intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    was measured at 9 Alginate Once Daily and _TIME_ on the baseline and day 28 visits, and at 9 Alginate Once Daily on day 2 and day 14 visits of each treatment period. The 9 Alginate Once Daily measurement was taken _POFT_ and _POFT_ after the last drop of unoprostone and latanoprost, and the _TIME_ measurement was at 10 and _POFT_, respectively. The mean of the measurements was calculated. Safety parameters were also recorded.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Fifty six patients completed both treatment periods and had intraocular pressure data available for evaluation. After _POFT_ of treatment, latanoprost significantly reduced intraocular pressure (mean +/ Standard Error Of MeanM) by
    <r1>
     6.1 +/ 0.5 mmHg
    </r1>
    _PVAL_ and unoprostone by
    <r2>
     4.2 +/ 0.4 mmHg
    </r2>
    _PVAL_ adjusted from an overall baseline of 22.3 +/ 0.5 mmHg and 23.2 +/ 0.4 mmHg, respectively. The difference of 1.9 mmHg between treatments was statistically significant in favor of latanoprost [_PVAL_, analysis of covariance ]. Unadjusted analysis of responders using the percentage decrease in intraocular pressure showed that the proportion of responders in the latanoprost treated group was greater than in the unoprostone treated group. Adverse ocular symptoms and findings were mild in both treatment groups. Eye redness and ocular irritation were the most frequently reported events.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Latanoprost once daily was significantly more effective in reducing intraocular pressure compared with unoprostone twice daily after _POFT_ of treatment in patients with primary open angle glaucoma and ocular hypertension. Both drugs were well tolerated with few ocular adverse events.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   A randomized double-masked crossover study comparing latanoprost 0.005% with unoprostone 0.12% in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma and ocular hypertension.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>