<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   12470755
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the intraocular pressure -lowering effect and safety of
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    0.005% once daily with that of
    <a2>
     unoprostone
    </a2>
    0.15% twice daily for
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with primary open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Randomized clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    In a prospective, 8-week, investigator-masked, parallel-group study conducted at numerous centers in the United States, 165 previously treated patients with Intraocular Pressure &gt;or= 25 mmHg in one or both eyes after washout were randomly assigned to receive either latanoprost 0.005% once daily in the evening or unoprostone 0.15% twice daily. Observations procedures were Goldmann applanation tonometry, best-corrected visual acuity, slit lamp biomicroscopy, and ophthalmoscopy. The main outcome measure was
    <oc>
     change
    </oc>
    in the mean of the Intraocular Pressures measured at 8:00 Alginate Once Daily, 12 noon, and 4:00 PM between baseline (before treatment) and after 8 weeks of treatment.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The change in the mean +/- Surgery , Mean of the Intraocular Pressures measured at 8:00 Alginate Once Daily, 12 noon, and 4:00 PM was
    <r1>
     -7.2 +/- 3.2 mmHg
    </r1>
    (28%) for latanoprost (25.3 +/- 2.8 mmHg at baseline to 18.2 +/- 2.8 mmHg at 8 weeks) and
    <r2>
     -3.9 +/- 2.6 mmHg
    </r2>
    (15%) for unoprostone (25.5 +/- 3.3 mmHg at baseline to 21.6 +/- 4.0 mmHg; P &lt;or=.001. No serious adverse event related to either medication was reported.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Over an 8-week period, latanoprost 0.005% once daily lowered Intraocular Pressure more than unoprostone 0.15% twice daily in patients with elevated Intraocular Pressure. Both agents were safe and well tolerated.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Randomized clinical trial of latanoprost and unoprostone in patients with elevated intraocular pressure.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>