<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   14704542
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy of intraocular pressure control of the Baerveldt 350
    <a1>
     implant
    </a1>
    with tube ligature and the Ahmed
    <a2>
     valve
    </a2>
    in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with refractory glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Four hundred seventy glaucoma drainage device procedures from _DATE_ to _DATE_ (_POFT_) were reviewed retrospectively. Thirty two cases of Baerveldt 350 implantation performed in patients with glaucoma refractory to medical treatment and filtering procedures, without previous drainage device or cyclodestructive procedures, and with a minimum of _POFT_ follow up were identified. Thirty two cases of Ahmed valve implantation were matched case by case with 32 Baerveldt 350 cases for age, race, gender, glaucoma subtype, previous ocular history, preoperative Intraocular Pressure, and surgeon who performed the implantation. The two groups were compared for Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     control
    </oc>
    , visual outcome, complication rate, and surgical success rate. Surgical success rate was defined as an Intraocular Pressure reduction greater than or equal to 30% and final Intraocular Pressure more than 5 mmHg and less than 22 mmHg, without devastating complications.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Over a follow up period of _POFT_, no statistically significant differences were detected between the Baerveldt 350 implant versus Ahmed valve for Intraocular Pressure control (
    <r1>
     12.1 +/ 5.3 mmHg
    </r1>
    versus
    <r2>
     13.6 +/ 5.6 mmHg
    </r2>
    respectively, at a power of 90% to detect a difference of 3.2 mmHg between the two groups and _PVAL_), surgical success rate (65.6% versus. 65.6% respectively, complete and qualified combined), postoperative hypotony rate (37.5% versus. 34.4% respectively), and visual acuity changes of more than 1 line in Snellen visual acuity (43.3% versus. 29.0% respectively).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    In a case controlled comparison, the Baerveldt 350 implant and the Ahmed valve had similar Intraocular Pressure control and surgical outcomes in patients with refractory glaucoma at _POFT_ follow up.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Baerveldt-350 implant versus Ahmed valve for refractory glaucoma: a case-controlled comparison.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>