<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   15220019
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="BACKGROUND" nlmcategory="BACKGROUND">
    The newer ocular hypotensive agents available to treat glaucoma and ocular hypertension include latanoprost, a prostaglandin F(2alpha) analogue, and the fixed combination of dorzolamide hydrochloride, a carbonic anhydrase inhibitor, and timolol maleate, a beta blocker.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="OBJECTIVE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    The aim of this study was to compare the efficacy and tolerability of
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    with that of the fixed combination of
    <a2>
     dorzolamide and timolol
    </a2>
    over _POFT_.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    This interventional, _POFT_, randomized, open label, parallel group study was conducted at 18 centers in 6 Latin American countries.
    <p>
     Patients
    </p>
    with unilateral or bilateral primary open angle, pigmentary, or exfoliative glaucoma or Ocular Hypertension were randomized to receive latanoprost, 1 drop in the affected eye QD (evening), or fixed combination dorzolamide/timolol, 1 drop in the affected eye BID (morning and evening). Medications were self administered, 1 drop per affected eye. At baseline and _POFT_, intraocular pressure was measured 3 times each at _TIME_, _TIME_, _TIME_, and _TIME_ and after the water drinking test, which estimates the Intraocular Pressure peak of diurnal tension curve, performed following the _TIME_ Intraocular Pressure assessment. The primary efficacy outcome was
    <oc>
     change
    </oc>
    in diurnal Intraocular Pressure (the mean of Intraocular Pressure measurements) from baseline to _POFT_. Adverse effect data were recorded at each visit.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    A total of 229 patients were randomized (latanoprost, _POP_; dorzolamide/timolol, _POP_). Mean baseline diurnal Intraocular Pressure values were similar between the 2 groups. Mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure reductions at _POFT_ before the water drinking test were
    <r1>
     6.9 (3.0) mmHg
    </r1>
    for the latanoprost group and
    <r2>
     6.4 (3.2) mmHg
    </r2>
    for the dorzolamide/timolol group. Mean Intraocular Pressure values were similar at all time points except at _TIME_, when levels were significantly lower in latanoprost treated patients _PVAL_. After the water drinking test, the increase in Intraocular Pressure values was similar between groups at baseline but lower in latanoprost treated patients at _POFT_ (adjusted difference, 1.08 mmHg; _PVAL_). Fewer patients treated with latanoprost reported ocular or systemic Adverse Effects (_PVAL_ and _PVAL_, respectively).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    In this study of patients with unilateral or bilateral primary open angle, pigmentary, or exfoliative glaucoma or Ocular Hypertension Intraocular Pressure reductions generally were similar between treatment groups, except at _TIME_, when the mean Intraocular Pressure level was significantly lower in latanoprost treated patients. Latanoprost was better tolerated than fixed combination dorzolamide and timolol.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Comparison of latanoprost with fixed-combination dorzolamide and timolol in adult patients with elevated intraocular pressure: an eight-week, randomized, open-label, parallel-group, multicenter study in Latin America.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>