<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   15234141
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To evaluate the efficacy and safety of Baerveldt and Ahmed glaucoma drainage implants in Asian
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with refractory glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Retrospective nonrandomized study.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PARTICIPANTS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Forty one patients.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    The authors reviewed the insertion of 18 Ahmed glaucoma valved
    <a1>
     implants
    </a1>
    and 24 350 mm(2) Baerveldt glaucoma
    <a2>
     implants
    </a2>
    performed by a single surgeon at the Department of Ophthalmology, National University Hospital, Singapore, from _DATE_, to _DATE_. A total of 42 glaucoma drainage implants was inserted into the eyes of 41 patients. All patients had at least _POFT_ of follow up.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    , visual acuity, and complications.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Both drainage implants achieved remarkable reductions in Intraocular Pressure; from pretreatment Intraocular Pressure of 40.1 +/ 13.8 mmHg and 43.7 +/ 9.3 mmHg to postoperative Intraocular Pressure of
    <r2>
     17.4 +/ 6.2
    </r2>
    and
    <r1>
     14.9 +/ 5.5 mmHg
    </r1>
    in the Baerveldt and Ahmed groups, respectively. A decrease in Intraocular Pressure of 56.6% and 65.9% had been achieved. Success rates were 20 _MEAS_ for Baerveldt and 12 _MEAS_ for Ahmed implants, whereas qualified success occurred in 1 _MEAS_ Baerveldt and 3 _MEAS_ Ahmed implants. Conversely, failure to control Intraocular Pressure occurred in 3 _MEAS_ Baerveldt implants and 3 _MEAS_ Ahmed implants. More than 80% of the patients had maintained or improved visual function, whereas only 4 _MEAS_ of the patients with Baerveldt implants and 2 _MEAS_ patients with Ahmed implants had loss of more than 1 Snellen line.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Both Baerveldt and Ahmed glaucoma drainage implants performed well in terms of Intraocular Pressure control, preservation of visual function, and having low complication rates.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Experience with the use of Baerveldt and Ahmed glaucoma drainage implants in an Asian population.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>