<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   15741820
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy and tolerability of
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    or
    <a2>
     brimonidine
    </a2>
    in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with elevated intraocular pressure .
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    This prospective, randomized, masked evaluator, parallel group, multicenter study in the United States included patients with primary open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension. Patients received latanoprost 0.005% once daily (_TIME_ Alginate Once Daily; _POP_) or brimonidine tartrate 0.2% twice daily (_TIME_ Alginate Once Daily and _TIME_; _POP_). Patients underwent evaluation at screening, baseline (randomization), and after 0.5, 3, and _POFT_ of treatment. Intraocular Pressure was measured at _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily, _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily, _TIME_, and _TIME_ at baseline and the _POFT_ and _POFT_ visits, and at _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily only at _POFT_. The main outcome measure was the difference in diurnal Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     change
    </oc>
    from baseline to _POFT_ between treatment groups. Adverse events were recorded at each visit.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Baseline mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure levels were similar between groups. At _POFT_, the adjusted mean ( +/ Standard Error Of MeanM) diurnal Intraocular Pressure reduction was
    <r1>
     5.7 +/ 0.3 mmHg
    </r1>
    in the latanoprost group and
    <r2>
     3.1 +/ 0.3 mmHg
    </r2>
    in patients receiving brimonidine _PVAL_. The mean difference in diurnal Intraocular Pressure reduction was 2.5 +/ 0.3 mmHg (95% Confidence Interval: 1.9, 3.2; _PVAL_). Five times more patients receiving brimonidine than latanoprost were withdrawn from the study due to adverse events.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Latanoprost instilled once daily is more effective and better tolerated than brimonidine administered twice daily for the treatment of patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension. During therapy, the range of daily fluctuation of Intraocular Pressure is less for latanoprost compared with brimonidine.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Latanoprost or brimonidine as treatment for elevated intraocular pressure: multicenter trial in the United States.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>