<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   16899528
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="AIMS" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare selective laser
    <a1>
     trabeculoplasty
    </a1>
    and argon laser
    <a2>
     trabeculoplasty
    </a2>
    , in terms of intraocular pressure  lowering, in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with open-angle glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    176 eyes of 152 patients were enrolled in this study, 89 in the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty and 87 in the Argon Laser Trabeculoplasty groups. Patients were randomised to receive either Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty or Argon Laser Trabeculoplasty treatment to 180 degrees of the trabecular meshwork. Patients were followed up to 12 months after treatment. The main outcome measured was Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     lowering
    </oc>
    at 12 months after treatment, compared between the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty and Argon Laser Trabeculoplasty groups.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    No significant difference (p = 0.846) was found in mean decrease in Intraocular Pressure between the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty (
    <r1>
     5.86 mmHg
    </r1>
    ) and Argon Laser Trabeculoplasty (
    <r2>
     6.04 mmHg
    </r2>
    ) groups at 1 year or at any other time points, nor were there any significant differences in the rate of early or late complications between the two groups.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty is equivalent to Argon Laser Trabeculoplasty in terms of Intraocular Pressure lowering at 1 year, and is a safe and effective procedure for patients with open-angle glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Selective laser trabeculoplasty versus argon laser trabeculoplasty: results from a 1-year randomised clinical trial.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>