<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   17083910
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To report one-year results of the Tube Versus Trabeculectomy  Study.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Multicenter randomized clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Setting: 17 Clinical Centers. Study Population:
    <p>
     Patients
    </p>
    18 to 85 years of age who had previous trabeculectomy and/or cataract extraction with intraocular lens implantation and uncontrolled glaucoma with intraocular pressure  &gt; or =18 mmHg and &lt; or =40 mmHg on maximum tolerated medical therapy. Interventions: 350 mm(2) Baerveldt glaucoma
    <a1>
     implant
    </a1>
    or
    <a2>
     trabeculectomy
    </a2>
    with mitomycin C . Main Outcome Measures:
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    , visual acuity, and reoperation for glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    A total of 212 eyes of 212 patients were enrolled, including 107 in the tube group and 105 in the trabeculectomy group. At one year, Intraocular Pressure (mean +/- Surgery , Mean) was
    <r1>
     12.4 +/- 3.9 mmHg
    </r1>
    in the tube group and
    <r2>
     12.7 +/- 5.8 mmHg
    </r2>
    in the trabeculectomy group (P = .73). The number of glaucoma medications (mean +/- Surgery , Mean) was 1.3 +/- 1.3 in the tube group and 0.5 +/- 0.9 in the trabeculectomy group (P &lt; .001). The cumulative probability of failure during the first year of follow-up was 3.9% in the tube group and 13.5% in the trabeculectomy group (P = .017).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Nonvalved tube shunt surgery was more likely to maintain Intraocular Pressure control and avoid persistent hypotony or reoperation for glaucoma than trabeculectomy with Mitomycin C during the first year of follow-up in the Tube Versus Trabeculectomy Study. Both surgical procedures produced similar Intraocular Pressure reduction at one year, but there was less need for supplemental medical therapy following trabeculectomy with Mitomycin C.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Treatment outcomes in the tube versus trabeculectomy study after one year of follow-up.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>