<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   17244215
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the ocular hypotensive efficacy and safety of topical
    <a1>
     bimatoprost
    </a1>
    and
    <a2>
     timolol-dorzolamide combination
    </a2>
    in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma  or ocular hypertension during 6 months of treatment.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    A sample of 65
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with a diagnosis of Primary Open-Angle Glaucoma or ocular hypertension were randomized to receive either bimatoprost 0.03% once daily or timolol-dorzolamide combination twice daily. Study visits occurred at baseline and after 2 weeks and 1, 3 and 6 months of therapy. Intraocular pressure  measurements were performed at 12.00 hours at all study visits and also at 08.00 hours and 16.00 hours at baseline and 6-month visits. At each visit, local and systemic side-effects that occurred during the treatment period were recorded. Student's t-test was used to compare the differences between Intraocular Pressure values.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Differences in Intraocular Pressure between the bimatoprost and timolol-dorzolamide groups were statistically insignificant at all study visits (p &gt; 0.05). In the bimatoprost-treated group, the Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     reduction
    </oc>
    was
    <r1>
     6.2 +/- 1.8 mmHg
    </r1>
    , whereas it was
    <r2>
     6.5 +/- 2.3 mmHg
    </r2>
    in the timolol-dorzolamide group after 6 months of treatment. The difference was not statistically significant (p = 0.48).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    The Intraocular Pressure-lowering efficacies of bimatoprost and timolol-dorzolamide combination were similar over a 6-month follow-up. Both bimatoprost and the timolol-dorzolamide combination were well tolerated. Bimatoprost can be used as a longterm monotherapy agent in the treatment of Primary Open-Angle Glaucoma and ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Comparison of the ocular hypotensive effects of bimatoprost and timolol-dorzolamide combination in patients with elevated intraocular pressure: a 6-month study.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>