<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   17293790
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="AIMS" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    The purpose of this randomized clinical trial was to compare the effectiveness and safety of
    <a1>
     viscocanalostomy
    </a1>
    (visco) with
    <a2>
     trabeculectomy
    </a2>
    (trab) in the management of primary open angle
    <p>
     glaucoma
    </p>
    .
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Patients were randomized to have a viscocanalostomy (25 eyes) or a trabeculectomy (25 eyes) performed by one surgeon and followed up prospectively. Patients were examined preoperatively, at day 1, day 3 if required, day 6, _POFT_ and thereafter as near as possible to 1, 3, 6, 12, 18, 24, 30, 36, 48, 54, and _POFT_. We recorded intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    , presence or absence of any complications, presence and description of any bleb, visual acuity with glasses, and full examinations as routine to monitor any progression of the glaucoma. Bleb interventions including needling and antimetabolites were allowed and recorded in both groups. YAG laser goniopuncture was allowed in the viscocanalostomy group.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Mean follow up was _POFT_ (Surgery , Mean 15), with a range from _POFT_ to _POFT_.
    <r2>
     Forty two percent
    </r2>
    (_POP_) of the patients in the trabeculectomy group had a successful outcome (Intraocular Pressure_CRI_ with no treatment) at last follow up visit, compared to
    <r1>
     21%
    </r1>
    (_POP_) in the viscocanalostomy group. Intraocular Pressure was lower in the trab group with differences in Intraocular Pressure being statistically significant at _POFT_2 _PVAL_, 24 _PVAL_, 30 _PVAL_, 36 _PVAL_, and 48 _PVAL_. The trabeculectomy group required less postoperative topical Intraocular Pressure lowering medication _PVAL_.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    In this study, we found trabeculectomy to be more effective at lowering Intraocular Pressure than viscocanalostomy in Primary Open Angle Glaucoma patients.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Viscocanalostomy versus trabeculectomy for primary open angle glaucoma: 4-year prospective randomized clinical trial.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>