<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   18402717
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="OBJECTIVE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of
    <a1>
     brimonidine
    </a1>
    purite 0.1% in comparison to
    <a2>
     brinzolamide
    </a2>
    1% when used as adjunctive therapy to latanoprost 0.005% in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Randomized, single center, investigator masked, parallel group clinical study. Patients with Intraocular Pressure _CRI_ while on once daily latanoprost were randomized to adjunctive treatment with brimonidine purite TID (_POP_) or brinzolamide TID (_POP_) for _POFT_. Intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    was measured at _TIME_, _TIME_, and _TIME_ at latanoprost treated baseline and after 1 and _POFT_ of latanoprost and adjunctive therapy. A patient questionnaire was administered to evaluate the tolerability of eye drop instillation.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Baseline mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure ( +/ standard deviation, mmHg) on latanoprost was comparable between groups (brimonidine purite: 19.6 +/ 2.94; brinzolamide: 19.8 +/ 3.25; _PVAL_). Mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure at _POFT_ was
    <r1>
     16.3 +/ 2.63 mmHg
    </r1>
    with brimonidine purite and
    <r2>
     17.8 +/ 2.19 mmHg
    </r2>
    with brinzolamide _PVAL_. Adjunctive use of brimonidine purite provided greater Intraocular Pressure lowering than brinzolamide at _TIME_ _PVAL_ and _TIME_ _PVAL_ and equivalent Intraocular Pressure lowering to brinzolamide at _TIME_ _PVAL_. Blurred vision at _POFT_ and bitter taste at _POFT_ and _POFT_ were more common upon instillation of brinzolamide eye drops.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Brimonidine purite 0.1% provided significantly lower Intraocular Pressure compared with brinzolamide 1% when used as adjunctive therapy to latanoprost. Both adjunctive therapies were well tolerated. Limitations of this study include the use of a single site and the sample size. Additional studies are needed to further evaluate these drugs as adjunctive therapy to prostaglandin analogs.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Brimonidine purite 0.1% versus brinzolamide 1% as adjunctive therapy to latanoprost in patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>