<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  ﻿
  <pmid version="1">
   18826749
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="OBJECTIVE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the Intraocular Pressure lowering efficacy of a.m. dosed
    <a1>
     travoprost
    </a1>
    and
    <a2>
     latanoprost
    </a2>
    at 24 h post dose.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Open angle glaucoma
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    not naïve to prostaglandin therapy and currently controlled on p.m. dosed (_YEAR_) latanoprost (_POP_) or travoprost (_POP_) had baseline Intraocular Pressures measured at 0900. In a randomized, single masked, crossover design, patients received travoprost (Travatan † ) or latanoprost (Xalatan ‡ ) at 0900 for _POFT_, then were crossed over to receive the second prostaglandin for another _POFT_. Treatment Intraocular Pressure was measured at 0900 prior to morning dose at both 4 and _POFT_ visits. Patient dosing preference (a.m./p.m.) was surveyed on exit. Main outcome measure: Intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    . † Travatan is a registered trade name of Alcon Laboratories, Inc., Fort Worth, TX, United states of america ‡ Xalatan is a registered trade name of Pfizer, New York, NY, United states of america.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The mean Intraocular Pressure in the first period when all patients were dosed in the evening was assessed 12 h after dosing at _TIME_ and it was similar in the two treatment groups (mean +/ standard deviation:
    <r1>
     17.9 +/ 2.7 mmHg
    </r1>
    for travoprost versus
    <r2>
     17.7 +/ 2.5 mmHg
    </r2>
    for latanoprost, _PVAL_). In the a.m. dosing crossover comparison, the 24 h post dose Intraocular Pressure was significantly lower ( _PVAL_) on travoprost (16.9 +/ 3.1 mmHg) compared to latanoprost (18.6 +/ 3.3 mmHg). In the exit survey, 51% of patients preferred a.m. dosing.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    a.m. dosed travoprost is superior to a.m. dosed latanoprost by 1.7 mmHg at 24 h post dose.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Comparison of morning versus evening dosing and 24-h post-dose efficacy of travoprost compared with latanoprost in patients with open-angle glaucoma .
  </title>
 </body>
</html>