<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   19092465
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy and tolerability of the fixed
    <a1>
     combination
    </a1>
    of timolol maleate 0.5%/brimonidine tartrate 0.2% versus fixed
    <a2>
     combination
    </a2>
    of timolol maleate 0.5%/dorzolamide 2% in patients with elevated intraocular pressure over _POFT_.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    This _POFT_, multicentric, interventional, randomized, open label, parallel group study was conducted at 4 centers in Brazil and 1 center in Argentina.
    <p>
     Patients
    </p>
    with open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension were randomized to receive bilaterally fixed combination of brimonidine/timolol maleate 0.5% or fixed combination of dorzolamide 2%/timolol 0.5% twice daily at _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily and _TIME_ A modified diurnal tension curve (_TIME_ Alginate Once Daily, _TIME_ Alginate Once Daily, _TIME_, and _TIME_) followed by the water drinking test , which estimates Intraocular Pressure peak of diurnal tension curve, were performed in the baseline and _POFT_ visits. Adverse events data were recorded at each visit.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    A total of 210 patients were randomized (brimonidine/timolol, _POP_; dorzolamide/timolol, _POP_). Mean baseline Intraocular Pressure was 23.43 +/ 3.22 mmHg and 23.43 +/ 4.06 mmHg in the patients treated with brimonidine/timolol and dorzolamide/timolol, respectively _PVAL_. Mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     reduction
    </oc>
    after _POFT_ were
    <r1>
     7.02 +/ 3.06 mmHg
    </r1>
    and
    <r2>
     6.91 +/ 3.67 mmHg
    </r2>
    , respectively _PVAL_. The adjusted difference between groups (analysis of covariance) at _POFT_ was not statistically significant _PVAL_. Mean baseline Water Drinking Test peak was 27.79 +/ 4.29 mmHg in the brimonidine/timolol group and 27.68 +/ 5.46 mmHg in the dorzolamide/timolol group. After _POFT_ of treatment, mean Water Drinking Test peaks were 20.94 +/ 3.76 mmHg _PVAL_ and 20.98 +/ 4.19 _PVAL_, respectively. The adjusted difference between groups (analysis of covariance) was not statistically significant _PVAL_. No statistical difference in terms of adverse events was found between groups.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Both fixed combinations were capable of significantly reducing the mean diurnal Intraocular Pressure, mean diurnal peak, and mean Water Drinking Test peak after _POFT_ of treatment. Also, both fixed combinations are well tolerated with few side effects.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   An eight-week, multicentric, randomized, interventional, open-label, phase 4, parallel comparison of the efficacy and tolerability of the fixed combination of timolol maleate 0.5%/brimonidine tartrate 0.2% versus fixed combination of timolol maleate 0.5%/dorzolamide 2% in patients with elevated intraocular pressure.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>