<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   19123151
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy and tolerability of a once daily evening dose of
    <a1>
     bimatoprost/timolol
    </a1>
    fixed combination with that of a once daily evening dose of
    <a2>
     latanoprost/timolol
    </a2>
    fixed combination in patients not controlled with prostaglandins analogues monotherapy.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    A total of 82
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    on prostaglandin analogues monotherapy were enrolled in this prospective, multicenter, investigator masked, clinical study and were randomized to either Bimatoprost/Timolol (_POP_) or Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination (_POP_) topical therapy once at night for _POFT_. The primary endpoint of the study was to compare the mean daily intraocular pressure
    <oc>
     reduction
    </oc>
    from baseline between the two treatment arms. Secondary endpoints included the mean daily Intraocular Pressure at 1 and _POFT_ compared to baseline and the percentage of patients showing a mean Intraocular Pressure reduction from baseline greater than or equal to 15% or 20%.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Mean Intraocular Pressure at baseline was 22.7 +/ 2.0 and 22.1 +/ 2.6 mmHg in the Bimatoprost/Timolol and Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination groups, respectively _PVAL_. Both treatments were effective in reducing the Intraocular Pressure from baseline. The mean Intraocular Pressure reduction was significantly greater in the Bimatoprost/Timolol group than in the Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination group (
    <r1>
     21.4%
    </r1>
    versus
    <r2>
     13.7%
    </r2>
    , _PVAL_). A higher percentage of patients in the Bimatoprost/Timolol group showed a mean Intraocular Pressure reduction from baseline _CRI_ (72.3% versus 40.0%) and _CRI_ (61.7% versus 17.1%) compared to patients in the Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination group.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Both Bimatoprost/Timolol and Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination were more effective versus the monotherapy with prostaglandin analogues. Bimatoprost/Timolol demonstrated higher performance than Latanoprost/Timolol Fixed Combination in terms of relative Intraocular Pressure reduction.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Efficacy of the fixed combinations of bimatoprost or latanoprost plus timolol in patients uncontrolled with prostaglandin monotherapy: a multicenter, randomized, investigator-masked, clinical study.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>