<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   19243831
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="OBJECTIVE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare
    <a1>
     phacoemulsification
    </a1>
    alone versus combined
    <a2>
     phacotrabeculectomy
    </a2>
    in medically uncontrolled chronic angle closure glaucoma with coexisting cataract.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Prospective randomized clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PARTICIPANTS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Fifty one medically uncontrolled Chronic Angle Closure Glaucoma
    <p>
     eyes
    </p>
    with coexisting cataract of 51 patients.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="INTERVENTION" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Recruited patients were randomized into group 1 (phacoemulsification alone) or group 2 (combined phacotrabeculectomy with adjunctive mitomycin C). Postoperatively, patients were reviewed every _POFT_ for _POFT_.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    and requirement for topical glaucoma drugs.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Twenty seven Chronic Angle Closure Glaucoma eyes were randomized into group 1, and 24 Chronic Angle Closure Glaucoma eyes were randomized into group 2. Combined phacotrabeculectomy resulted in lower mean postoperative Intraocular Pressure than phacoemulsification alone at _POFT_ (
    <r1>
     14.0
    </r1>
    versus
    <r2>
     17.0 mmHg
    </r2>
    , _PVAL_), _POFT_ (13.2 versus 15.4 mmHg, _PVAL_), and _POFT_ (13.6 versus 15.9 mmHg, _PVAL_). Combined phacotrabeculectomy resulted in 1.25 fewer topical glaucoma drugs _PVAL_ in the _POFT_ postoperative period, compared with phacoemulsification alone. Combined surgery was associated with more postoperative complications _PVAL_ and more progression of optic neuropathy _PVAL_, compared with phacoemulsification alone.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Combined phacotrabeculectomy with adjunctive mitomycin C is more effective than phacoemulsification alone in controlling Intraocular Pressure in medically uncontrolled Chronic Angle Closure Glaucoma eyes with coexisting cataract. Combined phacotrabeculectomy is associated with more postoperative complications.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Phacoemulsification versus combined phacotrabeculectomy in medically uncontrolled chronic angle closure glaucoma with cataracts.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>