<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   20472226
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy and safety of laser peripheral iridotomy with or without laser peripheral iridoplasty in the treatment of eyes with synechial primary angle closure or primary angle closure glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Randomized, controlled clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Consecutive
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    older than _POFT_ with synechial primary angle closure or primary angle closure glaucoma were recruited. Eligible patients were randomized to 1 of 2 treatment options,
    <a1>
     iridotomy
    </a1>
    or
    <a2>
     iridotomy
    </a2>
    plus iridoplasty, and were followed up for _POFT_. Main outcome measures were intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    , peripheral anterior synechiae, corneal endothelial cell count, and complications.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Seventy seven eyes (77 patients) were randomized to the iridotomy group, and 81 eyes (81 patients) were randomized to the iridotomy plus iridoplasty group. Sixty one patients _MEAS_ in the iridotomy and 65 patients _MEAS_ from the iridotomy plus iridoplasty groups completed _POFT_ of follow up. There were no significant differences between the groups in the baseline data. Intraocular Pressure was reduced from 24.66 +/ 13.76 mmHg to
    <r1>
     19.03 +/ 6.21 mmHg
    </r1>
    in the iridotomy group _PVAL_ and from 27.96 +/ 13.06 mmHg to
    <r2>
     20.45 +/ 7.26 mmHg
    </r2>
    in the iridotomy plus iridoplasty group _PVAL_. Extent of peripheral anterior synechiae was decreased by 1 more clock hour after iridoplasty compared with that after iridotomy in the iridotomy plus iridoplasty group _PVAL_. There was no significant difference in Intraocular Pressure, medications, need for surgery, or visual function between groups at the _POFT_ visit.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    In eyes with synechial primary angle closure or primary angle closure glaucoma, both iridotomy alone or combined with iridoplasty provide a significant and equivalent reduction in Intraocular Pressure. There is also a possible reduction in peripheral anterior synechiae, more so in the iridoplasty group.
   </abstracttext>
   <copyrightinformation>
    2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
   </copyrightinformation>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Laser peripheral iridotomy with and without iridoplasty for primary angle-closure glaucoma: 1-year results of a randomized pilot study.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>