<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   20733558
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    The aim of this study is to assess the efficacy and complications of
    <a1>
     trabeculectomy
    </a1>
    with a biodegradable implant (ologen implant) versus
    <a2>
     trabeculectomy
    </a2>
    using mitomycin C  in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with medically uncontrolled open-angle glaucoma in a prospective randomised clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    In the Mitomycin C group (10 patients), trabeculectomy was performed according to standard protocols. In the ologen group (10 patients) after standard trabeculectomy the implant was positioned on top of the scleral flap and no Mitomycin C was applied. Follow-up was continued for 12 months after surgery and included testing of intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    , visual acuity, visual field, ultrasound biomicroscopy, and filtering bleb score.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The mean preoperative Intraocular Pressure was 24.8 +/- 8.9 mmHg for all patients enrolled. At 1 year after surgery, the mean Intraocular Pressure was
    <r1>
     15.6 +/- 2.4mmHg
    </r1>
    in the ologen group (P&lt;0.01, 43% reduction) and
    <r2>
     11.5 +/- 4.1 mmHg
    </r2>
    in the Mitomycin C group (P&lt;0.01, 50% reduction). No anti-glaucomatous medication was necessary in the Mitomycin C group in the first year of follow-up, whereas five patients in the ologen group required topical treatment. The absolute success rate was 100% in the Mitomycin C group and 50% in the ologen group (P=0.01). After 1 year, filtering blebs developed significantly more avascular areas in the Mitomycin C group (score=1.4) than in the ologen group (score=2.8; P&lt;0.01).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    The complete success rate using trabeculectomy with the ologen implant is lower than that achieved by trabeculectomy with Mitomycin C. However, the bleb morphology caused more problems in the Mitomycin C group (avascularity score).
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   A prospective randomised trial of trabeculectomy using mitomycin C vs an ologen implant in open angle glaucoma.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>