<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   21543992
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare outcomes of selective laser
    <a1>
     trabeculoplasty
    </a1>
    with drug
    <a2>
     therapy
    </a2>
    for glaucoma patients in a prospective randomized clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Sixty nine
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    (127 eyes) with open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension were randomized to Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty or medical therapy. Target intraocular pressure was determined using the Collaborative Initial Glaucoma Treatment Study formula. Patients were treated with Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty (100 applications 360 degrees) or medical therapy (prostaglandin analog). Six visits over _POFT_ followed initial treatment. If target Intraocular Pressure range was not attained with Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty, additional Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty was the next step, or in the medical arm additional medications were added. Primary outcome:
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    ; secondary: number of steps.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Sixty nine patients were treated. Data collection terminated with 54 patients reaching _POFT_ to _POFT_ follow up. Twenty nine patients were in the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty group, 25 patients in the medical group. Baseline mean Intraocular Pressure for all eyes was 24.5 mmHg in the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty group, 24.7 mmHg in the medical group. Mean Intraocular Pressure (both eyes) at last follow up was
    <r1>
     18.2 mmHg
    </r1>
    (6.3 mmHg reduction) in the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty arm,
    <r2>
     17.7 mmHg
    </r2>
    (7.0 mmHg reduction) in the medical arm. By last follow up, 11% of eyes received additional Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty, 27% required additional medication. There was not a statistically significant difference between the Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty and medication groups.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Intraocular Pressure reduction was similar in both arms after _POFT_ to _POFT_ follow up. More treatment steps were necessary to maintain target Intraocular Pressure in the medication group, although there was not a statistically significant difference between groups. These results support the option of Selective Laser Trabeculoplasty as a safe and effective initial therapy in open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Selective laser trabeculoplasty versus medical therapy as initial treatment of glaucoma:  a prospective, randomized trial.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>