<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  ﻿
  <pmid version="1">
   21573097
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="OBJECTIVE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    The aim of this study was to compare the efficacy of augmenting trabeculectomy with subconjunctival
    <a1>
     mitomycin
    </a1>
    C versus
    <a2>
     5 fluorouracil
    </a2>
    in lowering intraocular pressure .
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Forty eyes from 40 patients referred to the Nikoukari Ophthalmology University Hospital, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran, were enrolled in a randomized clinical trial.
    <p>
     Patients
    </p>
    with high risk open angle glaucoma were allocated to receive either subconjunctival Trabeculectomy With Subconjunctival Mitomycin C or Tmmc ) Versus 5 Fluorouracil.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Mean overall preoperative Intraocular Pressure was 30.8 mmHg. Mean preoperative Intraocular Pressures in the Trabeculectomy With Subconjunctival Mitomycin C and Tmmc ) Versus 5 Fluorouracil groups were 31.2 +/ 9.8 and 30.6 +/ 9.9 mmHg, respectively. Postoperatively, mean
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressures
    </oc>
    were
    <r1>
     11.4.3 +/ 4.9
    </r1>
    and
    <r2>
     13.6 +/ 3.9 mmHg
    </r2>
    , respectively for Trabeculectomy With Subconjunctival Mitomycin C and Tmmc ) Versus 5 Fluorouracil groups after _POFT_. In spite of some existing descriptive differences in Intraocular Pressure between the groups, statistical tests showed no difference in mean and median Intraocular Pressure. Three cases of hypotonia (Intraocular Pressure _CRI_) and 1 case of epithelial keratitis were detected.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Trabeculectomy With Subconjunctival Mitomycin C and Tmmc ) Versus 5 Fluorouracil appeared to have similar efficacy in lowering Intraocular Pressure.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Augmenting trabeculectomy in glaucoma with subconjunctival mitomycin C versus subconjunctival 5-fluorouracil: a randomized clinical trial.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>