<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   21701528
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    The purpose of this study is to compare the safety and intraocular pressure -lowering efficacy of travoprost/timolol in a
    <a1>
     benzalkonium chloride -free fixed combination
    </a1>
    preserved with polyquaternium-1 (TRA/TIM Benzalkonium Chloride-free), with
    <a2>
     travoprost/timolol-fixed combination
    </a2>
    preserved with Benzalkonium Chloride , in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    In this prospective randomized controlled trial, subjects with Intraocular Pressure of at least 22 mmHg in one or both eyes at 0900 h, and Intraocular Pressure of at least 21  mmHg in one or both eyes at 1100  h and 1600  h at two eligibility visits were randomly assigned to receive either TRA/TIM Benzalkonium Chloride-free (n=195) or TRA/TIM (n=193), dosed once daily in the morning (0900  h) for 6 weeks.
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    was assessed at 0900  h, 1100  h, and 1600  h at each scheduled visit (baseline, 2 and 6 weeks after randomization).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Mean Intraocular Pressure reduction across all visits and time points was
    <r1>
     8.0 mmHg
    </r1>
    in the TRA/TIM Benzalkonium Chloride-free group and
    <r2>
     8.4 mmHg
    </r2>
    in the TRA/TIM group (P=0.0943). The difference in mean Intraocular Pressure between groups ranged from 0.2 to 0.7  mmHg across visits and time points, with a mean pooled difference of 0.4  mmHg (95% Confidence Interval: -0.1 to 0.8), demonstrating equivalence of the two formulations. The most common drug-related adverse event was hyperemia of the eye (ocular hyperemia and conjunctival hyperemia combined), occurring in 11.8% of the TRA/TIM Benzalkonium Chloride-free group and 13.0% of the TRA/TIM group.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Travoprost/timolol Benzalkonium Chloride-free demonstrated equivalence to travoprost/timolol preserved with Benzalkonium Chloride in efficacy. No clinically relevant differences in the safety profiles of travoprost/timolol Benzalkonium Chloride-free and travoprost/timolol preserved with Benzalkonium Chloride were identified.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Travoprost 0.004%/timolol 0.5%-fixed combination with and without benzalkonium chloride: a prospective, randomized, doubled-masked comparison of safety and efficacy.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>