<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   21921953
  </pmid>
  <title>
   Biodegradable collagen matrix implant vs mitomycin-C as an adjuvant in trabeculectomy: a 24-month, randomized clinical trial.
  </title>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="AIM" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To verify the safety and efficacy of Ologen
    <a1>
     implant
    </a1>
    as adjuvant compared with low dosage
    <a2>
     mitomycin C
    </a2>
    in trabeculectomy.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    This was a prospective randomized clinical trial with a _POFT_ follow up. Forty glaucoma
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    (40 eyes) were assigned to trabeculectomy with Mitomycin C or Of Ologen. Primary outcome includes target Intraocular Pressure at ≤21, ≤17, and ≤15 mmHg; complete (target Intraocular Pressure without medications), and qualified success (target Intraocular Pressure regardless of medications). Secondary outcomes include bleb evaluation, according to Moorfields Bleb Grading System ; spectral domain optical coherence tomography examination; number of glaucoma medications; and frequency of postoperative adjunctive procedures and complications.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The mean preoperative Intraocular Pressure was 26.5 ( +/ 5.2) in Mitomycin C and 27.3 ( +/ 6.0) in Of Ologen eyes, without statistical significance. One day postoperatively, the Intraocular Pressure dropped to 5.2 ( +/ 3.5) and 9.2 ( +/ 5.5) mmHg, respectively _PVAL_. The Intraocular Pressure
    <oc>
     reduction
    </oc>
    was significant at end point in all groups _PVAL_, with a mean Intraocular Pressure of
    <r1>
     16.0 ( +/ 2.9)
    </r1>
    and
    <r2>
     16.5 ( +/ 2.1) mmHg
    </r2>
    in Mitomycin C and Of Ologen, respectively. The rates and Kaplan Meier curves did not differ for both complete and qualified success at any target Intraocular Pressure. The bleb height in Of Ologen group was higher than Mitomycin C one _PVAL_. Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography analysis of successful/unsuccessful bleb in patients with or without complete success at Intraocular Pressure ≤17 mmHg indicated a sensitivity of 83% and 73% and a specificity of 75% and 67%, respectively, for Mitomycin C and Of Ologen groups. No adverse reaction to Of Ologen was noted.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Our results suggest that Of Ologen implant could be a new, safe, and effective alternative to Mitomycin C, with similar long term success rate.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
 </body>
</html>