<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  ﻿
  <pmid version="1">
   22775229
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    Ocular blood flow dysregulation has been implicated in the pathogenesis of glaucoma. Whereas the effect of single antiglaucoma substances on ocular blood flow has been addressed in various experiments, evidence for fixed combinations is sparse. In the present study, we set out to compare the effects of
    <a1>
     latanoprost 0.005%/timolol 0.5% fixed combination
    </a1>
    and
    <a2>
     brimonidine 0.2%/timolol 0.5% fixed combination
    </a2>
    on intraocular pressure and ocular blood flow.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    In the present study, which followed a randomized, double masked 2 way crossover design, 16
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with primary open angle glaucoma and 2 patients with ocular hypertension were included. The patients underwent a _POFT_ treatment with LT and a _POFT_ treatment with BT after a washout for previous antiglaucoma medication. Optic nerve head blood flow was measured using laser Doppler flowmetry; retrobulbar flow velocities were measured using color Doppler imaging in the ophthalmic artery, the central retinal artery, and the posterior ciliary arteries.
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    was measured at 8 Alginate Once Daily, _TIME_, and _TIME_
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The mean baseline Intraocular Pressure was 25.3 +/ 2.8 mmHg. Both drugs were equally effective in reducing Intraocular Pressure (LT:
    <r1>
     35.0% +/ 10.0%
    </r1>
    ; BT:
    <r2>
     33.6% +/ 8.8%
    </r2>
    , _PVAL_ between groups). In addition, no difference in ocular perfusion pressure was observed between the 2 treatment groups (_PVAL_, between groups). Neither LT nor BT altered Optic Nerve Head Blood Flow (_PVAL_, baseline versus. treatment) and no effect on flow velocities in the retrobulbar vessels was seen with either of the 2 treatments.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    In the present study, a _POFT_ treatment with LT or BT was equally effective in reducing Intraocular Pressure. In addition, none of the administered drugs induced a significant effect on ocular blood flow parameters.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   A double-masked randomized crossover study comparing the effect of latanoprost/timolol and brimonidine/timolol fixed combination on intraocular pressure and ocular blood flow in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>