<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  ﻿
  <pmid version="1">
   22814041
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To assess the long term safety and efficacy of a single trabecular micro bypass stent with concomitant cataract
    <a1>
     surgery
    </a1>
    versus cataract
    <a2>
     surgery
    </a2>
    alone for mild to moderate open angle glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="SETTING" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Twenty nine investigational sites, United States.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Prospective randomized controlled multicenter clinical trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    <p>
     Eyes
    </p>
    with mild to moderate glaucoma with an unmedicated intraocular pressure of 22 mmHg or higher and 36 mmHg or lower were randomly assigned to have cataract surgery with iStent trabecular micro bypass stent implantation (stent group) or cataract surgery alone (control group). Patients were followed for _POFT_ postoperatively.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    The incidence of adverse events was low in both groups through _POFT_ of follow up. At _POFT_, the proportion of patients with an Intraocular Pressure of 21 mmHg or lower without ocular hypotensive medications was significantly higher in the stent group than in the control group _PVAL_. Overall, the mean
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    was stable between _POFT_ and _POFT_ (
    <r1>
     17.0 +/ 2.8 mmHg
    </r1>
    and 17.1 +/ 2.9 mmHg, respectively) in the stent group but increased (
    <r2>
     17.0 +/ 3.1 mmHg
    </r2>
    to 17.8 +/ 3.3 mmHg, respectively) in the control group. Ocular hypotensive medication was statistically significantly lower in the stent group at _POFT_; it was also lower at _POFT_, although the difference was no longer statistically significant.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Patients with combined single trabecular micro bypass stent and cataract surgery had significantly better Intraocular Pressure control on no medication through _POFT_ than patients having cataract surgery alone. Both groups had a similar favorable long term safety profile.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="FINANCIAL DISCLOSURE" nlmcategory="BACKGROUND">
    Dr. Craven was an investigator in the clinical trial of the iStent. Dr. Katz is a consultant to Glaukos and was the medical monitor for the clinical trial of the iStent. Dr. Katz is a stockholder in Glaukos. Mr. Wells and Ms. Giamporcaro are employees of Glaukos.
   </abstracttext>
   <copyrightinformation>
    Copyright © _YEAR_ ASCRS and ESCRS. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
   </copyrightinformation>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Cataract surgery with trabecular micro-bypass stent implantation in patients with mild-to-moderate open-angle glaucoma and cataract: two-year follow-up.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>