<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   23429621
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy of
    <a1>
     bimatoprost/timolol
    </a1>
    or
    <a2>
     travoprost/timolol
    </a2>
    fixed combinations on intraocular pressure  reduction in an Egyptian population.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    <p>
     Patients
    </p>
    with primary open angle glaucoma were randomized to receive either Bimatoprost/Timolol or TTFC. Intraocular Pressures were measured at baseline, 2 weeks, and 1, 2, 4, and 6 months. The primary outcome measure was the mean
    <oc>
     change
    </oc>
    in Intraocular Pressure from baseline at each visit. Secondary outcome measures included the incidence of adverse events.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Eighty patients (80 eyes) were included finally: 40 eyes in each group. Baseline mean Intraocular Pressures were 24.78 +/- 3.53 and 25.26 +/- 3.51 mmHg for Bimatoprost/Timolol and TTFC, respectively (P=0.344). Both drops provided statistically significant Intraocular Pressure reductions from baseline at all visits (P&lt;0.001). Bimatoprost/Timolol provided greater significant mean Intraocular Pressure reductions from baseline than TTFC at each visit (P&lt;0.001). Mean Intraocular Pressure reductions were
    <r1>
     11.34
    </r1>
    and
    <r2>
     6.42 mmHg
    </r2>
    at 2 weeks (P=0.000), and 11.17 and 7.89 mmHg at 6 months (P=0.001) for Bimatoprost/Timolol and TTFC, respectively. Intraocular Pressures at 2 weeks were ≤18 mmHg in 36 (90.8%) versus 22 (55%) eyes and ≤16 mmHg in 28 (70%) versus 16 (40%) eyes (P&lt;0.001), and at 6 months, ≤18 mmHg in 38 (95%) versus 28 (70%) eyes and ≤16 mmHg in 30 (75%) versus 18 (45%) eyes for Bimatoprost/Timolol and TTFC, respectively (P&lt;0.001).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Both drops provided effective Intraocular Pressure reduction that was greater and patients were more likely to achieve lower target pressures with Bimatoprost/Timolol than with TTFC.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   Bimatoprost/timolol versus travoprost/timolol fixed combinations in an Egyptian population: a hospital-based prospective randomized study.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>