<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   24247999
  </pmid>
  <title>
   Prospective Randomized Study Comparing Ex-PRESS to Trabeculectomy: 1-Year Results.
  </title>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To compare the efficacy and safety of the
    <a1>
     Ex-PRESS
    </a1>
    glaucoma shunt with standard
    <a2>
     trabeculectomy
    </a2>
    .
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    Consenting
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with medically uncontrolled open-angle glaucoma were prospectively randomized to trabeculectomy or Ex-PRESS shunt both with mitomycin-C. Exclusion criteria included previous ocular surgery with the exception of clear cornea phaco or 1 previous trabeculectomy, uveitis, and vitreous in the anterior chamber. Standardized data collection sheets were completed at baseline and postoperative day 1, weeks 1 and 2, and months 1, 2, 3, 6, and 12. Primary outcome was intraocular
    <oc>
     pressure
    </oc>
    . Complete success was defined as an Intraocular Pressure between 5 and 18 mmHg and a 20% reduction from baseline without medication. A sample size calculation determined that 52 eyes were required to detect a 2.0 mmHg Intraocular Pressure difference with a power of 80%.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Sixty-four subjects were enrolled, 33 in the Ex-PRESS and 31 in the trabeculectomy group. Intraocular Pressure was not statistically significantly different between groups. Baseline and 1-year mean Intraocular Pressure was 22.0 +/- 6.8 versus
    <r1>
     22.7 +/- 10.3 mmHg
    </r1>
    (P=0.76) and 11.6 +/- 4.5 versus
    <r2>
     11.3 +/- 4.5 mmHg
    </r2>
    (P=0.81) in the trabeculectomy versus Ex-PRESS groups, respectively. Complete success was 57% versus 70% (P=0.28) in the trabeculectomy versus Ex-PRESS groups, respectively. There were no statistically significant differences in surgical time, number of glaucoma medications, visual acuity, central corneal thickness, endothelial cell counts, complications, interventions, or bleb morphology between the trabeculectomy and the Ex-PRESS groups.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    There was no statistically significant difference between the trabeculectomy and Ex-PRESS groups regarding Intraocular Pressure, success rates, complications, additional interventions, and bleb morphology.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
 </body>
</html>