<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   24844538
  </pmid>
  <title>
   Trabeculectomy With Mitomycin-C Versus Trabeculectomy With Amniotic Membrane Transplant: A Medium-term Randomized, Controlled Trial.
  </title>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">
    To evaluate the intraocular pressure -lowering effect of trabeculectomy with the use of amniotic membrane
    <a1>
     transplant
    </a1>
    compared with the standard trabeculectomy with
    <a2>
     Mitomycin-C
    </a2>
    in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    This study was a patient-masked, randomized, controlled comparison trial involving 52 eyes of 52
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with bilateral primary open-angle glaucoma. Patients were randomized to receive trabeculectomy with Alginate Once DailyT or trabeculectomy with Mitomycin C. The main outcome for comparison was the Intraocular Pressure-
    <oc>
     lowering
    </oc>
    effect of both procedures. Surgical success was considered if the patient's Intraocular Pressure was &lt;22 mm Hg, and the Intraocular Pressures were lowered by &gt;20% without the use of any medication.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    All surgeries passed uneventfully without intraoperative complications, and all patients showed significantly
    <r1>
     (P&lt;0.05)
    </r1>
    lower Intraocular Pressure on the first postoperative day compared with their respective preoperative Intraocular Pressure with nonsignificant (P&gt;0.05) difference between both study groups. All patients, irrespective of the operative procedure maintained significantly
    <r2>
     (P&lt;0.05)
    </r2>
    lower Intraocular Pressure compared with their respective preoperative Intraocular Pressure till the end of 24 months follow-up. Moreover, patients of the Alginate Once DailyT group showed lower Intraocular Pressure compared with those included in the Mitomycin C group throughout the follow-up period; however, the difference was not statistically significant at any point of the study period.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Alginate Once DailyT exhibits potential as an alternative to Mitomycin C in trabeculectomy surgery. Over 24 months of follow-up, the use of Alginate Once DailyT with trabeculectomy was safe and effective with an Intraocular Pressure-lowering effect comparable to that achieved with the use of Mitomycin C, and a reduced rate of postoperative complication.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
 </body>
</html>