<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   27157843
  </pmid>
  <title>
   Six-Month Intraocular Pressure Reduction with a Topical Bimatoprost Ocular Insert: Results of a Phase II Randomized Controlled Study.
  </title>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE">
    Improving adherence to manage elevated intraocular pressure  remains an unmet need. A topical
    <a1>
     bimatoprost
    </a1>
    ocular insert was compared with twice-daily
    <a2>
     timolol
    </a2>
    eye drops in
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with open-angle glaucoma  or ocular hypertension  treated for 6 months.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="DESIGN">
    Parallel-arm, multicenter, double-masked, randomized, controlled trial.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="PARTICIPANTS">
    One hundred thirty adult Open-Angle Glaucoma or Ocular Hypertension patients.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS">
    Eligible patients were randomized 1:1 to receive a bimatoprost insert plus artificial tears twice daily or a placebo insert plus timolol (0.5% solution) twice daily for 6 months after a screening washout period. Diurnal Intraocular Pressure measurements (at 0, 2, and 8 hours) were obtained at baseline; weeks 2, 6, and 12; and months 4, 5, and 6. Key eligibility included washout Intraocular Pressure of 23 mmHg or more at time 0, Intraocular Pressure of 20 mmHg or more at 2 and 8 hours, and Intraocular Pressure of 34 mmHg or less at all time points; no prior incisional surgery for Open-Angle Glaucoma or Ocular Hypertension; and no known nonresponders to prostaglandins.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES">
    The primary efficacy end point examined the difference in mean
    <oc>
     change
    </oc>
    from baseline in diurnal Intraocular Pressures (point estimate, 95% confidence interval) across 9 coprimary end points at weeks 2, 6, and 12 comparing the bimatoprost arm with the timolol arm using a noninferiority margin of 1.5 mmHg. Secondary end points were diurnal Intraocular Pressure measurements at months 4, 5, and 6 and adverse events (Adverse Effects).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS">
    A mean reduction from baseline Intraocular Pressure of
    <r1>
     -3.2 to -6.4 mmHg
    </r1>
    was observed for the bimatoprost group compared with
    <r2>
     -4.2 to -6.4 mmHg
    </r2>
    for the timolol group over 6 months. The study met the noninferiority definition at 2 of 9 time points but was underpowered for the observed treatment effect. Adverse events were consistent with bimatoprost or timolol exposure; no unexpected ocular Adverse Effects were observed. Primary retention rate of the insert was 88.5% of patients at 6 months.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS">
    Clinically relevant reduction in mean Intraocular Pressure was observed over 6 months with a bimatoprost ocular insert and seems to be safe and well tolerated. The topically applied bimatoprost insert may provide an alternative to daily eye drops to improve adherence, consistency of delivery, and reduction of elevated Intraocular Pressure.
   </abstracttext>
   <copyrightinformation>
    Copyright © 2016 American Academy of Ophthalmology. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
   </copyrightinformation>
  </abstract>
 </body>
</html>