<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   27269279
  </pmid>
  <title>
   Efficacy of Bevacizumab Compared to Mitomycin C Modulated Trabeculectomy in Primary Open Angle Glaucoma: A One-Year Prospective Randomized Controlled Study.
  </title>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="PURPOSE">
    To compare the efficacy of
    <a1>
     bevacizumab
    </a1>
    over
    <a2>
     mitomycin
    </a2>
    C  modulated trabeculectomy in cases of primary open angle glaucoma .
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHOD">
    In this prospective randomized controlled study, 80 eyes of 80
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    with uncontrolled Primary Open Angle Glaucoma or intolerant to antiglaucoma medications were randomized to two groups: Group 1 (n = 40) patients underwent trabeculectomy modulated with Mitomycin C (0.2 mg/ml), whereas Group 2 (n = 40) patients underwent trabeculectomy modulated with bevacizumab (1.25 mg/0.05 ml). The outcome measures were best corrected visual acuity , intraocular pressure , number of glaucoma medications and bleb morphological features based on Moorfields Bleb Grading System . All patients were followed up for one year post trabeculectomy.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS">
    The mean preoperative
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    in the bevacizumab group improved from 22.41 +/- 1.08 mmHg with 3.2 +/- 0.9 glaucoma medications to
    <r1>
     13.68 +/- 0.79 mmHg
    </r1>
    with 0.11 +/- 0.32 glaucoma medications at one year (P &lt; 0.001). The mean preoperative Intraocular Pressure in the Mitomycin C group improved from 22.64 +/- 0.90 mmHg with 3.1 +/- 0.8 glaucoma medications to
    <r2>
     13.84 +/- 0.73 mmHg
    </r2>
    with 0.17 +/- 0.38 glaucoma medications at one year (P &lt; 0.001). Intraocular Pressure was comparable between two groups at one year (P = 0.43). No significant differences were found in bleb morphological features based on Moorfields Bleb Grading System regarding central bleb area, peripheral bleb area, height and central vascularity between the two groups at six months and one year. However, there was a statistically significant difference in peripheral bleb vascularity and peripheral non-bleb vascularity with bevacizumab group exhibiting a low degree of vascularity at one year (P = 0.029 and 0.004, respectively).
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION">
    Adjunctive bevacizumab in trabeculectomy is effective and comparable to Mitomycin C for controlling Intraocular Pressure in Primary Open Angle Glaucoma patients for the first year.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
 </body>
</html>