<html>
 <head>
 </head>
 <body>
  <pmid version="1">
   9034838
  </pmid>
  <abstract>
   <abstracttext label="BACKGROUND" nlmcategory="BACKGROUND">
    Latanoprost is a Pigmentary GlaucomaF2 alpha analogue which reduces the intraocular pressure by increasing the uveoscleral outflow. The objective of this study was to investigate the effect of two different regimens of latanoprost on the diurnal Intraocular Pressure and also the effect of latanoprost on the blood aqueous barrier measured with a laser flare cell meter (Kowa FM 500). Moreover, the safety aspects of the two regimens regarding hyperemia were studied.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">
    A double masked, randomized study was performed in 30
    <p>
     patients
    </p>
    (9 males, 21 females; mean age _POFT_) with primary open angle glaucoma or pseudoexfoliation glaucoma. Twenty patients were treated with
    <a1>
     latanoprost
    </a1>
    0.0015% twice daily or 0.005% once daily for _POFT_ in a cross over design. Ten patients received
    <a2>
     timolol
    </a2>
    0.5% twice daily as control.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">
    Latanoprost 0.005% once daily reduced
    <oc>
     Intraocular Pressure
    </oc>
    ( +/ Standard Error Of MeanM) more effectively than latanoprost 0.0015% twice daily (
    <r1>
     9.8 +/ 0.9 mmHg
    </r1>
    and
    <r2>
     6.7 +/ 0.9 mmHg
    </r2>
    , respectively). There was a statistically significant increase in the aqueous humour protein concentration within the timolol group _PVAL_, but not within the latanoprost group _PVAL_. There was no statistically significant difference in the change in aqueous humour protein concentration from baseline between latanoprost and timolol groups _PVAL_. No statistically significant difference in conjunctival hyperemia between the two latanoprost regimens was found _PVAL_.
   </abstracttext>
   <abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">
    Latanoprost 0.005% once daily reduced Intraocular Pressure more effectively than latanoprost 0.0015% twice daily _PVAL_. Latanoprost had no statistically or clinically significant effect on the blood aqueous barrier. There was no difference in hyperemia between the two regimens. Both concentrations of latanoprost reduced Intraocular Pressure at least as well as timolol 0.5% eye drops.
   </abstracttext>
  </abstract>
  <title>
   The effect of latanoprost 0.005% once daily versus 0.0015% twice daily on intraocular pressure and aqueous humour protein concentration in glaucoma patients. A randomized, double-masked comparison with timolol 0.5%.
  </title>
 </body>
</html>