<pmid version="1">24844538</pmid>
<title>Trabeculectomy With Mitomycin-C Versus Trabeculectomy With Amniotic Membrane Transplant: A Medium-term Randomized, Controlled Trial.</title>
<abstract>
<abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the intraocular pressure (IOP)-lowering effect of trabeculectomy with the use of amniotic membrane <a1>transplant</a1> (AMT) compared with the standard trabeculectomy with <a2>Mitomycin-C</a2> (MMC) in patients with primary open-angle glaucoma.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">This study was a patient-masked, randomized, controlled comparison trial involving 52 eyes of 52 <p>patients</p> with bilateral primary open-angle glaucoma. Patients were randomized to receive trabeculectomy with AMT or trabeculectomy with MMC. The main outcome for comparison was the IOP-<oc>lowering</oc> effect of both procedures. Surgical success was considered if the patient's IOP was &amp;lt;22 mm Hg, and the IOPs were lowered by &amp;gt;20% without the use of any medication.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">All surgeries passed uneventfully without intraoperative complications, and all patients showed significantly <r1>(P&amp;lt;0.05)</r1> lower IOP on the first postoperative day compared with their respective preoperative IOP with nonsignificant (P&amp;gt;0.05) difference between both study groups. All patients, irrespective of the operative procedure maintained significantly <r2>(P&amp;lt;0.05)</r2> lower IOP compared with their respective preoperative IOP till the end of 24 months follow-up. Moreover, patients of the AMT group showed lower IOP compared with those included in the MMC group throughout the follow-up period; however, the difference was not statistically significant at any point of the study period.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">AMT exhibits potential as an alternative to MMC in trabeculectomy surgery. Over 24 months of follow-up, the use of AMT with trabeculectomy was safe and effective with an IOP-lowering effect comparable to that achieved with the use of MMC, and a reduced rate of postoperative complication.</abstracttext>
</abstract>