<pmid version="1">25847610</pmid>
<title>Trabeculectomy versus canaloplasty (TVC study) in the treatment of patients with open-angle glaucoma: a prospective randomized clinical trial.</title>
<abstract>
<abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the outcomes of <a1>canaloplasty</a1> and <a2>trabeculectomy</a2> in open-angle glaucoma.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">This prospective, randomized clinical trial included 62 <p>patients</p> who randomly received trabeculectomy (n = 32) or canaloplasty (n = 30) and were followed up prospectively for 2 years. Primary endpoint was complete (without medication) and qualified success (with or without medication) defined as an intraocular <oc>pressure</oc> (IOP) of ≤18 mmHg (definition 1) or IOP ≤21 mmHg and ≥20% IOP reduction (definition 2), IOP ≥5 mmHg, no vision loss and no further glaucoma surgery. Secondary endpoints were the absolute IOP reduction, visual acuity, medication, complications and second surgeries.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">Surgical treatment significantly reduced IOP in both groups (p &amp;lt; 0.001). Complete success was achieved in <r1>74.2%</r1> and 39.1% (definition 1, p = 0.01), and <r2>67.7%</r2> and 39.1% (definition 2, p = 0.04) after 2 years in the trabeculectomy and canaloplasty group, respectively. Mean absolute IOP reduction was 10.8 ± 6.9 mmHg in the trabeculectomy and 9.3 ± 5.7 mmHg in the canaloplasty group after 2 years (p = 0.47). Mean IOP was 11.5 ± 3.4 mmHg in the trabeculectomy and 14.4 ± 4.2 mmHg in the canaloplasty group after 2 years. Following trabeculectomy, complications were more frequent including hypotony (37.5%), choroidal detachment (12.5%) and elevated IOP (25.0%).</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">Trabeculectomy is associated with a stronger IOP reduction and less need for medication at the cost of a higher rate of complications. If target pressure is attainable by moderate IOP reduction, canaloplasty may be considered for its relative ease of postoperative care and lack of complications.</abstracttext>
<copyrightinformation>© 2015 The Authors. Acta Ophthalmologica published by John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Acta Ophthalmologica Scandinavica Foundation.</copyrightinformation>
</abstract>