<pmid version="1">28887006</pmid>
<title>A 3-month safety and efficacy study of travoprost 0.004% ophthalmic solution compared with timolol in pediatric patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension.</title>
<abstract>
<abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate efficacy and safety of travoprost in pediatric patients with ocular hypertension or glaucoma and demonstrate its noninferiority to timolol.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">Patients aged 2 months to &amp;lt;18 years with glaucoma or ocular hypertension were randomized to receive travoprost (0.004%) or timolol eye drops (0.25% for patients aged 2 months to &amp;lt;3 years and 0.5% for patients ≥3 years old) for 3 months in this double-masked, parallel-group study. Intraocular pressure (IOP) was measured and patients were evaluated at 2 weeks, 6 weeks, and 3 months after treatment. Change in IOP from baseline to 3 months was the primary endpoint, and the test of noninferiority was based on a margin of +3.0 mm Hg using the 95% 2-sided confidence interval of the mean change.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">Of 157 patients included (mean age, 9.6 years), 77 received travoprost and 75 timolol. All patients experienced a significant reduction in IOP in the study eye at 3 months: the mean IOP change from baseline was -5.4 mm Hg for travoprost; -5.3 mm Hg, for timolol. The mean difference between travoprost and timolol at month 3 was -0.1 mm Hg (95% CI, -1.5 to 1.4 mm Hg). The most common treatment-related adverse events for the travoprost group were ocular hyperemia and eyelash growth. No serious adverse events were reported.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="CONCLUSIONS" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study found travoprost to be noninferior to timolol in lowering IOP in patients with pediatric glaucoma or ocular hypertension. Travoprost was well-tolerated, and no treatment-related systemic adverse events were reported.</abstracttext>
<copyrightinformation>Copyright © 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</copyrightinformation>
</abstract>