<pmid version="1">29133641</pmid>
<title>Simultaneous use of amniotic membrane and Mitomycin C in trabeculectomy for primary glaucoma.</title>
<abstract>
<abstracttext label="PURPOSE" nlmcategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to propose the role of amniotic membrane transplantation (AMT) as an additional modulator in primary Mitomycin C (MMC)-augmented trabeculectomy.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="METHODS" nlmcategory="METHODS">This was a randomized prospective interventional study. Forty eyes of 39 adult patients with uncontrolled primary glaucoma were randomly divided into two equal groups. Control group underwent trabeculectomy augmented with MMC while the study group underwent additional AMT. Patients were followed up for 12 months and outcomes measured were intraocular pressure (IOP), need for additional intervention, and bleb morphology.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="RESULTS" nlmcategory="RESULTS">Complete success (defined as IOP &amp;lt;16 mmHg on no medication) could be achieved in 85% eyes in study group while it was 60% in control group (P = 0.04). IOP reduced by 71.1% in study group from 41.9 ± 10.6 to 12.1 ± 2.7 mmHg and from 40.5 ± 8.5 to 12.8 ± 4.5 mmHg in control group, a decline of 68.29%. Blebs in AMT group showed better bleb morphology in terms of significantly better extent (E3) on day 1 (P = 0.03) and better height (H2 and H3) (P = 0.04), according to the Indiana Bleb Appearance Grading Scale, at all follow-up visits along with normal vascularity. The study group required significantly lesser (P = 0.03) bleb needlings as compared to control group.</abstracttext>
<abstracttext label="CONCLUSION" nlmcategory="CONCLUSIONS">Amnion enhanced the efficacy of MMC-modulated trabeculectomy in terms of eyes with complete success and lesser interventions such as bleb needling. This reiterates the role of amnion as a safe and effective bleb modulator. A diffusely elevated bleb with healthier conjunctiva can go a long way in predicting better health and longevity of the bleb.</abstracttext>
</abstract>